How to Connect RGB LED with Arduino

The common negative connection of the LED package is the second pin from the flat side of the LED package. It is also the longest of the four leads. This lead will be connected to ground.

For testing purposes, check your LED datasheet for its pin-out or below are the two most common RGB LED form factors and pin-outs. The following is an example:

FH2D167FX8OUGEI.MEDIUM

Wire up the Test Schematic (below)

Connect a current limiting resistor (270Ω) to each of the three cathodes
Connect the common anode to 5V
Test each color by connecting its current limiting resistor to ground
Experiment with colour mixing a little by powering multiple elements at once
Each LED inside the package requires its own resistor to prevent too much current flowing through it. The three positive leads of the LEDs (one red, one green and one blue) are connected to Arduino output pins using these resistors.
